ねえ 当麻(とうま)
Hey, Touma.
Are you really going to school starting today?
今日から
本当に学校行っちゃうのかな
Oh, that's right.
（上条(かみじょう)）
うん？　そっか　お前
ずっと留守番になっちまうのか
You're going to be home alone from now on.
ンッ… 私は別に 寂しいとか
１人がイヤだとか
I didn't say that I'd be lonely or that I don't like being alone; it's not like that!
そういうことを
言っているんじゃないんだよ
う～ん… これから どうするか
一度 よく考えなきゃな
We need to take the time and actually think about what to do about this.
But, sorry, be home alone for today.
（上条）
悪い
今日は とりあえず留守番 頼むわ
Touma, will you come home as soon as you can?
当麻 早く帰ってくる？
I guess.
そうだな　帰ったら
一緒に どっか遊びに行くか
Let's go hang out somewhere once I get back.
わあ！　うん！
OK!
（上条）じゃ 行ってくる
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）うん いってらっしゃい
I'll be going then.
Yeah, have a good day.
フフッ…
それじゃ 何して遊ぼっかな
Well, what are we going to play today?
フフフン フフフン♪
Huh?
あれ？　当麻 お昼ご飯は？
Touma, what about my lunch?
What should I do...
どうしよう　未曽有の大ピンチかも
～♪
This is a huge crisis I have yet to face...
#21 Counter Stop
Unknown Entity
Shocker...
Yo.
（上条）オッス！
（美琴(みこと)）うん？
All fired up already, eh?
（上条）
朝っぱらから元気だな おい
随分 のんびりしてるわね
You sure seem relaxed.
Well yeah...
まあな
いろいろあったから疲れてんだよ
So much has happened, and my body's tired.
W-What?!
な… なによ
昨日の恋人ごっこって
そんなに疲れる仕事だったわけ？
Was yesterday's "boyfriend" game that tiring for you?
うん？　う～ん…
まあ それ１つじゃないんだけどな
Hey, that's not the only factor.
１つじゃない？
Not the only...
まさか あんた
ほかの女の子とも あんなことを…
Are you saying... you're doing that kind of thing for other girls, too?!
...You're the only one who would calmly ask me
to do such embarrassing things, okay?!
あ… あんな こっ恥ずかしいこと
平然と頼んでくるヤツなんて―
お前しかいねえわ！
You think I asked you calmly?!
平然って
そんなわけないでしょう！
私だって メチャクチャ悩んで
それでも ほかに打開策がなくて
Even for me, I didn't know what to do...
...and since I couldn't come up with any other solution...
しかたなく
恥を忍んで頼んだっていうのに！
...I swallowed the embarrassment and...
...begged you to do it!
Uhh, yeah, sure, uh huh, it's just like you say.
（上条）
ああ　はいはい
そうだね　そのとおりだね
Hey, wait!
（美琴）
こら！
ちょっと真面目に聞きなさいよ！
Listen to me seriously!
September 1st.
（上条）
９月１日　２学期の始業式
The first day of the second semester.
But, having lost my memories during summer vacation,
だが 夏休み中に
記憶を失った俺にとっては―
I have the nervous feeling
transfer students have on the first day.
転入初日と同じような 微妙な
緊張感を感じていたりするわけで
Komoe-sensei?
小萌(こもえ)先生…
...Her feet can reach the brakes?
…て ブレーキに足 届くのか？
I can drive even if my feet can't reach the brakes!
（小萌）
足が届かなくったって
運転できるんです！
まったく…
Gosh!
Sensei doesn't remember raising you in such a bad manner, Kamijyo-chan!
先生は上条ちゃんをそんなふうに
育てたつもりはないです
Sensei... that's not a pop quiz, is it?
先生　それ
抜き打ちテストじゃないですよね？
先生が 自分が学生時代にやられて
イヤだと思ったことは やりません
Sensei wouldn't do something to her own students that she, herself, hated.
A friend requested that I gather some data.
友人に
資料集めをお願いされてるんです
It's a white paper on AIM dispersion field.
ＡＩＭ拡散力場に関する文献です
What's umm...
（上条）
何です？　その…
"An Involuntary Movement",
（小萌）
“An Involuntary Movement(アン インボルンタリー ムーブメント)”
in other words, lack of self-consciousness.
“無自覚”ということです
Basically, it's when an esper emits
a field of power like the sun emitting light.
（小萌）
簡単に言えば 能力者が
体温のように発してしまう―
力のフィールドのことですね
Granted, these are so weak that they can't even be measured.
もっとも 計測できないぐらい
微弱なものなんですけど
（上条）
ふ～ん… じゃ
それを読み取れる能力者がいたら
Then, if there was an esper that could detect those,
“うん？
近くに能力者の気配がする”
they can say "Hey! There's a presence of an esper nearby" or something?
…なんてことが
できるってことですか？
Yes!
はい　更に進歩すれば―
And further down the line, they might even be able to distinguish the type or magnitude of the power, too.
能力の種類や強さを
測ることができるかもしれません
"Mmm... his Power Level is 70000!"
“ムムッ…
ヤツの戦闘力は７万ポイントだ”
...something like that,
…みたいな感じで
and basically, there are people who devote their passion to that kind of research.
…と まあ 世の中には―
そんなことに情熱を注いでる
物好きさんたちもいるのです
Thanks for bringing me here every time.
（土御門(つちみかど)）
ありがとう　いつも すまないにゃ
Hey, what's going on?
おい どうなっているんだ？
簡単に魔術師の侵入を許すとは
Allowing a magician to break into this city so easily.
It doesn't matter.
（ｱﾚｲｽﾀｰ）
かまわぬよ　侵入者の所在は
こちらでも追跡している
I am tracing the location of the intruder as we speak.
Shelley Cromwell.
（土御門）
シェリー＝クロムウェル
She's not a vagrant magician, but a member of the English Purist Church, Necessarius.
流れの魔術師ではなく―
イギリス清教
必要悪の教会(ネセサリウス)の人間だ
If she's taken down without care, then the status quo between the Church and Academy City will be ruptured.
ヘタに倒せば
学園都市との間に亀裂が走る
For both "neighbor loving" sides
to be breathing down each other's throats...
（ｱﾚｲｽﾀｰ）
隣人を愛する者同士が
いがみ合うとは
Anyway, have me take out Shelley.
（土御門）
とにかく 俺はシェリーを討つぞ
If a magician takes out a magician,
then the commotion will be smaller.
同じ魔術サイドの手で討てば
波も小さくなる
There is no need for you to do anything.
（ｱﾚｲｽﾀｰ）
君は手を出さなくていい
まさか… また上条当麻を？
Don't tell me... you want to have Kamijyo Touma handle this again?!
It can shorten the time between Plan 2082 and Plan 2377.
（ｱﾚｲｽﾀｰ）
プラン2082から2377までを
短縮できる
Is that the control theory of the Imaginary Number Sector - Five Elements Institution?
（土御門）
虚数学区 五行機関の制御法か
For it is a restive horse that could rip apart the entire world,
何せ
世界を引き裂くほどの暴れ馬だ
and it would be best to have a
firm grip of the reins before it's too late.
手綱は 早く
つかみ直したほうが無難だろう
Huh?
（上条）あれ？
（青髪ﾋﾟｱｽ）うん？
What's up, Kami-yan?
（青髪ﾋﾟｱｽ）どうしたん カミやん
（上条）土御門は？
Where's Tsuchimikado?
ああ　そういえば まだ見てへんな
Yeah, we haven't seen him yet, huh?
Maybe he didn't finish his homework.
まさか 宿題 終わってないとか
Hey, look at me,
僕なんか
小萌先生に怒られるためだけに―
I purposely left them on the backburner just so that Komoe-sensei could give me a scolding!
あえて 全部 忘れてきましたよ
Hey now...
（上条）
あのな…
Okay children, time to begin homeroom.
は～い　ホームルーム始めますよ
Before the starting ceremony, I have big news for you all.
始業式の前に
みんなにビッグニュースです
And wow, we have a new transfer student in our class today.
なんと
今日から 転入生 追加なのです！
Oh, it's a girl, by the way.
ちなみに 女の子ですよ
おめでとう 野郎ども！
Congratulations, goons!
残念でした 子猫ちゃんたち
Better luck next time, kitties.
さあ！　転入生ちゃん どうぞ！
Okay, transfer student, come on in!
えっ？　インデックス
Index?!
Ah, it's Touma!
あっ 当麻だ！
やっぱり ここが
当麻の通う学校なんだね
This was your "school" after all!
ど… どっから入ってきたんですか
転入生は あなたじゃないでしょう
Where did you come from?!
You're not the transfer student!
ほら　出てった 出てったです！
Come on, get out, get out.
もう シスターちゃん
なんだって こんな所に…
Sister-chan, what are you doing here?
Here.
ほら　これでタクシーに乗って
まっすぐ お家(うち)に帰ってください
Use this and get a taxi to go straight home.
And don't follow strangers, okay?
それから くれぐれも知らない人に
ついてっちゃダメなのですよ
By the way, the real transfer student is me...
（姫神(ひめがみ)）
ちなみに 本物の転入生は私
...Himegami Aisa.
姫神秋沙(あいさ)
I'm hungry...
（おなかの鳴る音）
おなか減った
ムッ… 聞いたことある
確か 食べ物の引換券が出てくる
Mmm, I've heard of this.
Coupons that can be exchanged for food come out from them.
Touma makes fun of me and calls me an "antique",
当麻は私を“アンティーク”って
バカにするけど
このくらい簡単
but this is a piece of cake.
Put in the money.
お金を入れて…
And just press the button.
ボタンを押すだけ
Huh?
…て あれ？
ボタンは？　ボタンがない！
Where's the button?
There's no button!
What should I do?
どうしよう
お金も のみ込まれちゃったんだよ
The money got eaten, too!
Umm...
（風斬(かざきり)）あの…
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）うん？
（風斬）
ボタン 押さなくちゃ
You need to press the button.
There's no button anywhere.
ボタンなんか どこにもないんだよ
Well, just touch the monitor.
だから モニターを触れば…
えっ？
でも テレビの中の人には触れない
But I can't touch the people inside the TV.
This TV is linked with the inside, huh?!
このテレビ
中とつながってるんだね
No, umm...
いや あの…
Thank you!
ありがとう　あなた 名前は？
What's your name?
I'm Kazakiri Hyouka.
私 風斬氷華(ひょうか)
And then, you know?
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
それでね
私は当麻の名前を呼んだのに
I called Touma's name,
but not only did he not answer me,
he turned his eyes somewhere else!
答えてくれないどころか
目をそらしたんだよ
（風斬）
う～ん… でも 学校って
部外者が入っちゃいけない所だから
Well, school's not a place for outsiders to come.
But, Hyouka, so are you...
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）でも 氷華だって…
（風斬）私は転入生だから
I'm a transfer student.
I'm going to become a transfer student, too, then!
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）私も転入生になる！
（風斬）えっと…
Umm...
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
このまま黙って帰るのはイヤだし
There's no way I'm going back home like this,
and what's most important is that I need to ask what to do about lunch!
何より
お昼ご飯が どうなっているのか
問いたださないと
But your attire is too distinctive...
でも その格好じゃ 目立ち過ぎるし
あっ… じゃ どうすればいいの？
Then, what should I do?
（風斬）あの…
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）うん？
Umm...
あそこに行けば もしかしたら…
If we go to that place, then maybe...
（上条）
俺が言うのも何だけど
I know it's weird for me to be saying this,
but she's the type that gets into trouble quite easily.
あいつも あいつで トラブルに
巻き込まれやすいタチだからな
It stretches well, and it's a fabric that gets cleaned very easily.
（風斬）
よく伸びるし
汚れが落ちやすい生地だし
Wow!
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
すご～い！
それって ハイテクってやつだね
This is what they call "high tech" right?
Damn you, stupid Sister!
おのれ　バカシスター
おい　インデックス！
Hey Index!
What the hell are you doing in a place like... this...
（上条）
てめえ
こんな所で何してるんだ …よ？
Sorry, wrong room-
ま… 間違えまし…
Touma!!!
当麻！
ハァ… 今日は始業式だから
昼までには帰れるっつうの
It's just the opening ceremony today, so I would've been home by noon.
How would I know that?!
そんなの分かんないもん！
こんぐらい常識だろう
This is common sense.
ンッ… じゃ 当麻は分かる？
Then, Touma, did you know this?
イギリス仕込みの十字架に
テレズマを込める―
The direction and standing position of the caster in the formula used...
偶像作りのための儀式上における
術式を行うときの―
...during the idol creation ritual of injecting telesma into crucifixes made in England?
方角と術者の立ち位置の関係とか
Get it wrong just by a little, and it won't function at all.
少しでも外れると
機能しなかったりするんだけど
そういった黄金比は分かる？
ほらほら こんなの常識だよ
Do you know that golden ratio, huh?
See, see, this is common sense, eh~
So, Index, who is she?
…で インデックス　そちらは？
うん？
よく分かんない　でも 友達
I'm not sure, but she's my friend.
（上条）
“よく分かんない”って
You're not sure?
ンッ… よく分かんなくても
氷華は友達だもん
I'm not sure, but Hyouka's my friend!
あっ 私は風斬氷華っていいます
My name is Kazakiri Hyouka.
あっ… 俺は上条当麻
I'm Kamijyo Touma.
Are you a transfer student?
（上条）転入生か？
（風斬）は… はい
Y-Yes-
Touma!
当麻！
氷華を怖がらせちゃダメなんだよ
Don't be scaring Hyouka here!
（上条）えっ？
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）大丈夫だよ 氷華
Don't worry, Hyouka.
当麻は 血気盛んで 優柔不断で
Touma's hot-blooded and indecisive,
女の子に片っ端から
関わっていくような人種だけど
and if it involves girls, he's the type that'll dive right into problems for her,
まあ いい人だから
but, he's a good person.
Here, I'll let you hold onto Sphinx.
ほら スフィンクス貸してあげる
猫に触るとガチガチが取れるかも
You could relieve your nervousness by touching a cat, maybe.
（風斬）
スフィンクスって名前？
Is Sphinx... his name?
（鳴き声）
（風斬）わあ…
あっ…
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）どうしたんだろう
What's the matter?
Animals are much more cunning than humans,
動物は人間よりも鋭いから
私とあなたの違いが分かるのかも
so he could probably tell the difference between you and me.
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
ふ～ん…
（小萌）上条ちゃん
（上条）ハッ…
Kamijyo-chan!
（小萌）
２学期初日から いい度胸なのです
You sure got some guts already on the first day of second semester!
Huh, Sensei, shouldn't you be at the ceremony...
（上条）
あれ？　先生 今 始業式じゃ…
先生は
体育館に上条ちゃんの姿がないから
Sensei didn't see you at the hall, so she got worried and came looking for you!!!
心配して 来たんですよ
Yet, Kamijyo-chan, you-
（小萌）なのに 上条ちゃんは…
（上条）いや あの…
No, umm, I-
ンンッ…
なんだって上条ちゃんの所には―
Why is it that girls always trickle down to you wherever you are, Kamijyo-chan?!
女の子が
転がり込んでくるんですか？
変なＡＩＭ拡散力場でも
生みだしているんですか？
Do you possess a weird kind of AIM dispersion field?
What the...
なんだ そりゃ
Why don't you say something, too, Kazakiri-
なあ　風斬も何か言ってやって…
Huh?
（上条）…て あれ？
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）うん？
（上条）
あきれて帰っちまったのか？
She had enough and left?
（風斬）あの…
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）あっ 氷華
Umm...
Hyouka.
It was wild back there, huh?
なんか すごかったね
ちょっと びっくりしちゃった
I was a bit shocked.
Komoe isn't mad or anything.
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
小萌のあれは怒ってるんじゃないよ
そんなに気にすることないよ
You don't have to worry about it too much.
You seem to have some sadness about you.
（風斬）
何か悲しそうな顔してる
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
当麻 怒ってた
Touma was mad at me.
全然 私の言葉 聞いてくれないし
ちっとも笑ってくれないし
He didn't hear anything I said.
He didn't smile at all.
当麻
私のこと嫌いになっちゃったのかな
Has Touma started to dislike me?
ケンカのできる友達って
ホントは すごく仲がいいの
Friends that are able to fight with each other are the ones that are really close.
Why?
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
どうして？
ケンカができるっていうことは
ちゃんと仲直りができるの
The fact they can fight means they can forgive each other properly afterwards.
It's like you can trust that person to not cut off the relationship even after a fight.
（風斬）
あの人は
ケンカしても縁が切れないって―
信じてるんだと思う
ホントに？
Really?
He's a person who would get angry over something for your sake,
あなたのために
怒ってくれるような人だから
so it'll be fine.
きっと大丈夫
人の裸を見ても
平気な顔で話しかけてくるけど
Although he's also a person who would come talk to you calmly even after seeing you naked...
（上条）お～い！
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）当麻！
Hey.
Touma!
Let's go eat.
（上条）
じゃ メシ食いに行くか
We're not eating at home today?
今日は家で食べないの？
We're going out after we eat anyway.
どうせ
メシ食ったら 遊びに行くんだし
Would you mind joining us, Kazakiri?
（上条）
風斬も どうだ？
（風斬）えっ？
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）そうだ
Yes, join us, Hyouka!
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）氷華も一緒に行こう
（風斬）いいの？
Is that okay?
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）行こう 行こう
（風斬）えっと…
Let's go, let's go!
フフッ… ありがとう
Thank you!
う～ん… あれ？
ちょっと金下ろしてくるから
Let me go withdraw some cash.
うん？　姫神…
Himegami.
I transfer here, and now you give me this cold reaction?
人が転校してきたというのに
その淡泊な反応は？
私 やっぱり影が薄い女なのね
I'm a girl who goes unnoticed after all, huh?
Ah, no... right!
いや あの…
そうだ
これから遊びに行くんだけど
We're going to hang out somewhere, won't you join us?
（上条）お前も どうだ？
（姫神）あっ…
あっ… 小萌のバカ
...stupid Komoe...
（上条）うん？
（姫神）何でもない
Nothing.
用事を頼まれているから
私は行けない
I was asked to run an errand, so I can't go.
That aside, who is she?
そんなことより あの人は？
風斬氷華 …だったかな
Kazakiri Hyouka, I think.
本当に風斬氷華なのね？
You're sure she's Kazakiri Hyouka, right?
Yeah, Index said so, and she said her name, as well.
ああ　本人もインデックスも
そう言ってるけど　知り合いか？
You know her?
（風斬）霧ヶ丘(きりがおか)女学院
（上条）うん？
Kirigaoka Girls' School.
The high school I attended before.
私が前に通ってた高校
そこでも風斬氷華の名前は見た
I saw Kazakiri Hyouka's name there too.
Then is she a user of a rare kind of power like you?
じゃ あいつも お前みたいな
珍しい能力の持ち主なのか？
（風斬）分からない
（上条）うん？
I don't know.
Her name always showed up
on the top rankings of test results,
（姫神）
彼女の名前は いつも―
テストの上位ランカーとして
貼り出されていたけど
but no one ever saw her in person.
実際に彼女の姿を見た者はいない
どのクラスに所属しているのかすら
No one even knew which class she was in.
What's up with that?
（上条）
何だよ それ
That's when I got curious and investigated a little.
それで 気になって調べたの
そうしたら 分かった
It was then that I found out.
彼女は
“正体不明(カウンターストップ)”と呼ばれていると
She's called "Counter Stop".
However, that's not the important part.
（姫神）
でも
いちばん重要なのは そこじゃない
風斬氷華は 虚数学区 五行機関を
知るためのカギだと
Kazakiri Hyouka has been called the key to understanding the Imaginary Number Sector - Five Elements Institution.
五行機関？　そんなもんが本当に？
The Five Elements Institution?
That thing really exists?
Rumor has it this Institution is the one that controls the administration of Academy City from the shadows.
（姫神）
ウワサでは 学園都市の運営を
陰から掌握してるって
彼女には 彼女個人の能力を
調べるための―
A special research facility was established just for researching her ability.
特別クラスがあったらしいの
それは 虚数学区 五行機関の
正体を探るための研究室だって
So, it is a research center dedicated to discovering the truth of the Imaginary Number Sector - Five Elements Institution.
その彼女が どうして ここに？
What is a person like her doing here?
She said she is a transfer student.
転入生だって言ってたけど
I should be the only transfer student.
（風斬）転入生は私しかいないはず
（上条）うん？
Be careful.
気をつけてね
これがウワサの地下世界なんだね！
This must be...
...the famous "Underworld"!
You mean, underground mall.
地下街な 地下街
Underground mall.
Index, is there something you'd like to eat?
インデックス
何か食いたい物(もん)とかあるか？
Expensive places and places with long lines
are out of the question!
高いとこと
行列ができるとこは禁止な
I want somewhere cheap, abundant in amount, delicious in quality, and not too popular!
高くて おいしくて 量が多くて
あまり人に知られてないお店がいい
（上条）はいはい　風斬は？
（風斬）えっ？
Yeah, yeah.
What about you, Kazakiri?
俺が何かしましたか？
Did I do something wrong?
（風斬）
あっ いえ
怖いとかじゃないんですけど
No.
I'm not scared or anything...
裸も見られたし…
You've seen my body already...
（上条）えっ？
（風斬）あっ いえ
No!
Secret tea time with an outsider girl, eh?
（黄泉川）
部外者の女の子と 秘密のお茶会ね
If only the elite kids in my class would pull something reckless like that, too...
ウチのクラスの優等生たちも
そんくらいムチャしてくれればね
Gosh, you Anti-Skills have a problem here!
もう！　あなたたち警備員(アンチスキル)にも
問題があるのですよ
What if this outsider were a dangerous person!
侵入者が危険人物だったら
どうするんですか？
Yeah, yeah.
…で 例の部外者―
So, I heard there were two of these outsiders.
２人いたじゃん
っていう話なんだけど
I wanted to confirm one thing really badly with you.
ひとつだけ確認しときたくてね
本当に２人いたのかなって
Were there really... two of them?
Yes, Yomikawa speaking.
はい　黄泉川
すぐ向かう
I'm on my way.
警備員(アンチスキル)のお仕事ですか？
Anti-skill work?
Looks like we got a big one.
でかい捕り物があるみたい
I'll be out for a bit.
ちょっくら行ってくる　そんじゃね
See ya~
I brought you the book you asked for.
頼まれてた本 持ってきた
AIM Dispersion Fields for Dummies
（小萌）
あっ ご苦労さまです 姫神ちゃん
Thank you, Himegami-chan.
（風斬）小萌先生
（小萌）はい？
Komoe-sensei.
Yes?
Is there a student called Kazakiri Hyouka at this school?
この学校に
風斬氷華っていう生徒は？
There she is.
（黒子(くろこ)）
いましたわね
（生徒）
あっ 避難命令だ！
It's an evacuation order!!
I'd prefer if you wouldn't move at all.
（黒子）
動かないでいただきたいですわね
I serve in the law enforcement unit of this city,
私 この町の治安維持を
務めております―
風紀委員(ジャッジメント)の白井(しらい)黒子と申します
Shirai Kuroko of Judgment.
自身が拘束される理由は
わざわざ述べるまでもないでしょう
I'm sure you don't need us to tell you the reason we're going to arrest you.
Search halted.
探索中止　手間かけさせやがって
Giving me extra work...
I said not to move.
動くなと申し上げております
Don't understand Japanese?
日本語 正しく伝わってませんの？
何です？
What is this?!
Impossible!
まさか
外部の人間のくせに能力者？
A normal human who's also an esper?
This is not good!
マズイですわ　とにかく体勢を…
I have to retreat-
I'm not sure what this fuss is about...
（美琴）
何の騒ぎか知らないんだけどさ
私の知り合いに
手ぇ出してんじゃないわよ！
...but don't be touching my friends, damn it!!!
（黒子）ハッ…
（美琴）もう大丈夫よ
It's okay now.
That huge hand was just a diversion.
あのでっかい手は
囮(おとり)だったみたいだから
The fact that you're after this person means...
あんたが追ってるってことは…
Yes, it was apparently an intruder.
ええ　どうやら
不法侵入者みたいでしたけど
Oneesama!!!
（黒子）お姉様～！
（美琴）こら！
Hey!
（黒子の泣き声）
…たく
Geez...
Kuroko, it's okay to rely on me more.
黒子
もっと私を頼っていいんだからね
迷惑かけたくないなんて思わないの
Don't think about not causing me trouble.
This is such a rare chance!
（黒子）
これぞ まさしく
千載一遇のチャンスですわ！
こうして近づけば
お姉様の胸の谷間へと思う存分…
Being this close, I can enjoy Oneesama's cleavage as much as I want...
（美琴）
ちょ… ちょっと！
黒子 そういうことじゃない…
Hold it, Kuroko, that's not what I meant...
Widespread even before the era before Noah's Ark,
（ｼｪﾘｰ）
過去には ノアの箱舟以前に広まり
今も 本来とは異なる方法で―
using bits of knowledge passed on by the chief of the Grigoris,
グリゴリの長(おさ)より伝えられる
断片的知識より
now, in a method different from the original...
"In the beginning, there was primal clay."
まずは原初に土
"God created a form from the clay,
bestowed life upon it, and called it 'Man'."
神は 土より形を作り 命を吹き込み
これに“人”と名を付けた
その秘法は やがて―
"This secret was passed to Man through the oral tradition of the fallen angels."
地に落つる堕天によって
人へと口伝される
"However, this was a secret too great for Man to handle."
しかして その御業(みわざ)は
人の手になせるものにあらず
"Thus, the life borne from my hand halts at a decaying mud doll."
かくして 私の手によって
生みだされし命は―
腐った泥の人形止まり …と
Mud-stinking golem, Ellis.
泥くさいゴーレム＝エリス
私のために 笑って使いつぶされな
Laugh and decay at my bidding.
Don't make me wait too long, Ellis.
あんまり待たせんなよ エリス
～♪
Next Episode
（上条）
魔術師 シェリー＝クロムウェルが
操る怪物 エリス
The monster that Shelley Cromwell controls, Ellis.
地下街に閉じ込められた俺たちは
激しい戦闘に巻き込まれる
Being stuck in the underground mall,
we get caught in an intensive battle.
風斬 お前の秘密って…
Kazakiri, what's your secret?!
Next time, "Golem".
次回 「石像(ゴーレム)」
科学と魔術が交差するとき
物語は始まる
When science and magic cross paths,
this epic will begin!